A Finding Aid to the Leon Golub Papers, 1930s-2009, in the Archives of American Art AAA.goluleon
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, 1959-2005; Series 5; 6.2 Linear feet Boxes 5-11, OV 18
  - Golub, Paul (photocopies 1983-1986), undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gordon, Avery, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Gould, Roy, 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Graham Foundation for Advanced Study in the Fine Arts, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Griffelkunst, 1993-1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Griffin Contemporary, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Hardware, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Head Hunt, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
  - Heads, 1950s-1960s (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Heads and Combats, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Heckscher Museum of Art "Millennium Messages" (1999 November 29-2001 January), 1998-2000 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Hiroshima Art Prize, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Hiroshima City Museum of Contemporary Art, 1995-1998; Includes 1 videocassette (VHS) (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
  - Hopper House Art Center, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Horodner, Stuart, 1996-2001 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Human Rights Exhibition, "The Voice of Art," U.N. Geneva (2004 March 14-April 25), 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Images (Source Material) (Box 7)
    - Animals, Miscellaneous, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Blacks, Threnody, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Classical, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Conversing, Site, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Current, Active, undated; 1990s-2000s (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Current, Active, for Drawing Center, undated; 1990s (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Current Drawings, undated (Box 7, Folder 37-40)
    - Dead Man and Woman, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Drawings, Graffiti, etc., undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Drawings, Small Paintings, undated (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
    - G, N, [and Vietnam], 1960s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Gestures, 1980s-circa1990s (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Guns, udated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Lions, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Mercenaries, Interrogations, 1980s; undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Older Men, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Older Men, Standing, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Politicians, 1970s; undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Prisoners, undated (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
    - Prisoners, The Arrest, undated; 1980s-1990s (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Prisoners, Victims, Heads, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Riots, Go-Ahead, undated; 1980s (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Sandwiched", 2003; 1 Videodiscs (DVD) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sphinx, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - These Colors, etc., 1988; undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Unsorted, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - White Squad, H.A., undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Instructions for Hanging Canvases, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Instructions for Installation of Photographic Transparencies, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Instructions for the Ironing of Leon Golub Painting, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Interns, 1990s (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Irish Hunger, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, "Threads of Dissent" (1999 October 20-2000 January 30), 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Janus Avivson Gallery, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Josh Baer Gallery, 1984-1994 (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Josloff Gallery, University of Hartford, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Kartequin Films, 1987-2001 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Kunce, Samm, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Kunsthalle, Wein, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - "Kwangju Bienniale 2000" (2000 March 29-June 7), 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - "Law and Order Show" (1986 September 19-25) (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Lectures and Visits, 1996-2003 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Legal Information for Artists, 1970s-1990s (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - "Leon Golub Paintings, 1950-2000," Albright Knox Art Gallery (2001 January-April 15), 2000-2001; undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - "Leon Golub Paintings, 1950-2000," Brooklyn Musuem of Art (2001 May 18-August 19) (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - "Leon Golub Paintings, 1950-2000," Irish Museum of Modern Art (2000), undated; 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 38-42)
  - "Leon Golub, While the Crime is Blazing: Paintings and Drawings: 1994-1999" (2000), Liane and Danny Taran Gallery, Saidye Bronfman Center for the Arts, 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Loft Law, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - "Lookout" (Box 9)
    - "Lookout", 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Houston (2000 October 7 – December 3), 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - London (2000 September 15-November 11) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Miami (1999 September 15-November 28) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - New York (1999 February 11-May 16) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - San Francisco (2000), 2000-2001 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lublijana, Slovenia, 2001-2004 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Magnolia Tapestry Project, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Malmö Kunsthalle, circa 1970s-circa 2000 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Markers, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Markers 2, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Mary Washington College Gallery, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Museum of Contemporary Art (MassMOCA), 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - McGraw-Hill, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Michael Rosenfeld Gallery, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Musée d'Art Contemporain de Montréal, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Musée National d'Arte Moderne, Pompidou Center, "Face à l'Histoire" (1996 December 19-1997 April 7), 1995-1997 (Box 9, Folder 17-18)
  - Museo Jacob Borges, 1997-2000 (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
  - Museum of Contemporary Art, Chicago, 1994-1998 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Museum of Contermporary Art, Los Angeles, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "Nancy Spero and Leon Golub: War and Memory" (1994), M.I.T. List Art Center and the American Center in Paris, 1992-1995; Includes 2 videocassettes: VHS (Box 9, Folder 23-24)
  - Namibia, "The Hope and Optimism Portfolio: A Global Art Project", 1991 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - National Gallery of Canada, 1999-2003 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Neuendorf, Hans, ( Kissinger II and Kissinger IV), 1987-1998 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - 2004 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - New York Kunsthalle, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Not in Our Name, etc., 2002-2004 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Obrist, Hans Ulrich, 1994-2003 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Old Glory (Continued), 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Pacific Northwest College of Art, "Carnival in the Eye of the Storm, War/Art/New Technologies: KOSOVO" (2000 April 6-29) (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Pergamon Project, 1998-1999 (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
  - Peru, American Embassy, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Portraits of Power (executed 1970s), 1980s-2000 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Possibilities for Barion, circa 1990s-circa 2000s (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - P.P.O.W., 2003 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - "Presence of Greek Myth," Instituto di Storia dell'Arte (1998 May 9-September), 1997-1998 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - The Print Center, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "Prints and Drawings – Part I" (2004 February 6-April 4), Seraphin Gallery (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Prints and Drawings – Part II" (2004 February 26-March), Rosemont College (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Printworks, 1985-2003 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Prisoners, 1990; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 10, Folder 4)
    POV program entitled "Through the Wire"
  - Projects, Events, 2000s (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Public Art Fund (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Rachette, Anne, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Recommendations, 1981-2004; undated (Box 10, Folder 8-9)
  - Red Sphinx, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Relaxation Instructions, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Residenzgallerie, Salzburg Project, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Rhona Hoffman Gallery, 1989-2004 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Rod Rogers Dance Company, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Romania, 1996-2000 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Ronald Feldman Fine Arts, 1993-2004; undated (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
  - Roth/Horowitz Gallery, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Seated Boxer I, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Seraphin Book, Don't Tread on Me! Leon Golub Drawings: 1947-2004 (Box 10, Folder 20-21)
  - Seraphin Gallery, 2002-2004 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Slome, Manon, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Sommerakademie, 1994-2000 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - South London Gallery, 2000-2003 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Stedelijk Museum (S.M.A.K.) Exhibition (2000) (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Straus, David Levi, 2003; undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Studio Stefania Miscetti, 1993-1999 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Tate Modern, Vietnam II (1973), 2003 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Temple Shalom of Chicago, Stained Glass Window, 1995-2003 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Tufts University Gallery, 2004; Includes 1 electronic disc (CD) (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - University of Maryland, Fine Arts Gallery, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - University of Massachusetts, Amherst, "The Culture of Violence" Tour (2002 January-2003 May), 2001-2003 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee, "Between the Global and the Local: Making Human Rights Claims in the 21st Century" Conference (2000 April 28-29), 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Utopia," a formation by Hans-Ulrich Obrist and Molly Nesbit (2003 April 11-September 29), 2002-2003; Includes 1 electronic disc (DVD) (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Valencia, "A Sangre y Fuego" (1999 October 6-December 12) (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Vancouver Art Gallery, 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Venice Banner, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Visual Artists and Galleries Association (VAGA), 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Von der Heydt-Museum, Wuppertal, undated; 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Wayne State University, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - WBAI Radio Program about the Intellectual, Political and Artistic Climate of Early 20th Century Berlin, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Weimar Installation, "The Violence Zone" (1995-June 24-July 30), 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Subject File Material from Box 6, Folder 37, 1950 (Box OV 18)
- Personal Business Records, 1965-2009; Series 6; 1.4 Linear feet Boxes 11-12
  This series consists mainly of inventories and lists that document Golub's artistic output of drawings, paintings, sculpture, prints. "Painting and Sculpture History" (photocopy) is a comprehensive, chronological register of work. Among the miscellaneous lists are: gifts, canvases in flat files, rolled paintings in studio, and items in basement. There is information about gifts and donations, including works in trust and those owned by the Spero Golub Family LLC. Also included are files concerning consignments, loans, photo permissions, and extensive mailing lists.
  Files are arranged alphabetically.
  - Condition Reports, 2008-2009; undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Consignments, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Gifts and Donations (1946-2003), undated; 1988-2003 (Box 11, Folder 8-9)
  - Inventories (Box 11)
    - Golub Active and Spero Active, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
    - Available Drawings, 2001-2003 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Available Paintings, 2002-2004; undated (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
    - Available Paintings, Corrected Inventory, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Available Paintings in Collections, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Available Prints, 1990-1997 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Erotic Drawings, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Inventory Lists, undated; 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Painting and Sculpture, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Political Portraits, 1989-1999; undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Prints, Nancy Spero and Leon Golub Trust, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Small Paintings and Drawings, undated; 2002-2004 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Lists, Miscellaneous, undated; circa 1970s-2003 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Loans, 1992-2004 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
  - Mailing Lists, 1992-1994; undated (Box 11, Folder 29-30)
  - Mailing Lists, 1994-2001 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - Painting and Sculpture History (1946-1991) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Painting Records to be Corrected, circa 1970s-circa 1990s (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Paintings in Collections, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Photo Permissions and Fees, 1990s-2004; undated (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
  - Price Lists (1987-2004), 1990-2004; undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Print Documentation (1946-1990s), 1965-2002; undated (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
  - Restoration, 1994; undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Slide Lists, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Sold (1946-2004), undated; 1987-2004 (Box 12, Folder 13-14)
  - Sotheby's Catalog, Notes for Valuations, 1981-2004; undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Spero Golub Family LLC, 2002-2004 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Works in Storage, undated; 1993-2009 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Printed Material, circa 1950s-2009; Series 7; 3.9 Linear feet Boxes 12-16, 21, OV 19
  Most printed material is about/mentions Golub and/or includes reproductions of his work. Clippings from newspapers and periodicals (many photocopies) represent the largest portion of this series. They include feature articles, reviews, gallery advertisements, letters to the editor and other writings by Golub. Also included in this series are exhibition catalogs and checklists, exhibition announcements, and miscellaneous printed items. Scattered throughout are items concerning topics of interest to Golub, and articles written by him.
  Additional printed material is found with biographical materials (Series 1), with Golub’s writings (Series 4), and is found in many subject files (Series 5).
  - Book Covers, 1980s-2000s (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Books, 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
  - Brochures, 1990s; undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, 1948-1966; undated (Box 12, Folder 22-27)
  - Clippings, 1967-1987 (Box 13, Folder 1-27)
  - Clippings, 1988-2002 (Box 14, Folder 1-23)
  - Clippings, 2003-2009 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
  - Conference/Symposium Announcements and Programs, 1966-2001 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Announcements, undated; 1966-2009 (Box 15, Folder 7-10)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Checklists, undated; circa 1950s-2000 (Box 15, Folder 11-20)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Checklists, 2001-2005 (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Film and Book Announcements, 1988-1998; undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Announcements and Programs for Events with Golub Speeches, circa 1970s-1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1979-2004; undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters and Calendars of Events, 1955-2003 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Posters, 1970; undated; Oversized material housed in OV 19 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Reproductions, 1986-2001; undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Oversized Posters from Box 16, Folder 7, undated (Box OV 19)
  - Clippings (published 1971-1977), 1970s (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Announcements, circa 1960-1976 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, circa 1960-1975 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1964-1974 (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
  - Periodicals ( Caterpillar)with Reproductions of Work by Golub, 1967-1971 (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
- Photographs, 1940s-2004; Series 8; 0.6 Linear feet Boxes 16-17, OV 20
  Photographs of people include portraits of Leon Golub and Nancy Spero, their sons, and his father, Samuel Golub. Portraits include Golub as an elderly man and as a younger man, sometimes posed in front of his artwork. There also are photographs of friends or colleagues at exhibition events, and a series of color snapshots of a young child at an exhibition. The vast majority of materials are color digital prints of artwork produced by Golub, 1981-2004. Also included are photographs of Golub's plexibox sculptures.
  Additional photographic materials are included among the subject files (Series 5).
  - People, 1940s-1997; undated; Oversized material housed in OV 20 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Artwork by Leon Golub (Box 16)
    - Art Items/Bronzes (executed 1992), undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Athletes (executed 1999-2004), undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Cyborgs (executed 1999-2002), undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Dogs (executed 1999-2004), undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - DWG/Digital (executed, 1999-2003), undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Eagles (executed 1999-2002), undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Erotica (executed undated, 2000-2004) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - Inkjet Images (undated, 1959-1982) (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Lions (executed 1999-2003), undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Male Figures (executed 1999-2004), undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (executed 1981-2004), undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Mythology (executed 1999-2004), undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Plexibox Images (executed undated, 1999) (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Skeletons (executed 1994-2004), undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Violence (executed 1999-2003), undated (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
    - Women (executed 1999-2004), undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Photographs of People from Box 16, Folder 9, 1996-2002 (Box OV 20)